Imagine you’re an alien sent to Earth to document the behaviour of the mammals inhabiting the planet.
想象一下，你是一个外星人，被派到地球来记录栖居在这颗星球上的哺乳动物的行为。
You stumble into a movie theatre that’s showing the latest Hollywood horror film.
你误打误撞走进一家电影院，那里正在放映好莱坞最新的恐怖片。
Several dozen humans are gathered together in a dark, undecorated room.
几十个人类聚在一间黑暗、毫无装饰的屋子里。
They’re all staring at a rectangular area on which patterns of light change rapidly.
他们全都盯着一块长方形区域，上面的光影图案飞快地变换着。
They are clearly in a state of high arousal.
他们显然处于高度兴奋的状态。
Their heart rate is elevated, they occasionally glance around nervously, and they sometimes jump collectively in their seats, and emit high-pitched warning calls.
他们心率升高，偶尔紧张地四下张望，有时还会在座位上集体惊跳起来，发出尖厉的报警叫声。
Eventually, the lights come up and the rectangular screen goes black.
最后，灯光亮起，那块长方形的屏幕变黑了。
The humans stand up and leave the room, chatting and laughing, and showing signs of pleasure.
这些人类站起身，离开屋子，有说有笑，流露出愉悦的神色。
Why do these humans voluntarily expose themselves to what appears to be a deeply unpleasant experience?
这些人类为什么要自愿置身于一种看上去极不愉快的体验之中呢？
And why do they react so strongly to those patterns of light on a screen?
他们又为什么会对屏幕上那些光影图案反应如此强烈呢？
I am fascinated with the paradox of horror—the strange fact that many people seek out scary entertainment.
我对恐怖悖论很着迷，它指的是这样一个奇怪的事实：许多人会主动寻求吓人的娱乐。
I think the answer to the puzzle lies in human nature.
我认为，这个谜题的答案在于人性。
My research suggests that we humans evolved to find pleasure in situations that allow us to experience negative emotions in a safe context.
我的研究表明，我们人类经过进化，会从那些让我们能在安全的环境里体验负面情绪的情境中获得愉悦。
You can see these elements of horror in children’s games.
你可以在儿童游戏中看到这些恐怖元素。
Take hide-and-seek, for example, which is a simulation of a predator-prey interaction.
就拿捉迷藏来说，这种游戏模拟的是捕食者与猎物之间的互动。
The kid hides and the adult pretends to be a predator, searching for the child while howling like a dangerous beast.
孩子躲起来，大人则假扮捕食者，一边寻找孩子，一边像危险的野兽那样嚎叫。
This simulation gives the child crucial information about how to avoid becoming prey, and children tend to find that kind of activity deeply satisfying, presumably because it gives them a safe experience of a potentially catastrophic scenario.
这种模拟为孩子提供了关于如何避免沦为猎物的关键信息；孩子们往往会从这类活动中获得极大的满足，这大概是因为它让他们得以安全地体验一种潜在的灾难性情境。
They find it pleasurable, and pleasure is evolution’s way of motivating us toward adaptive behaviour.
他们觉得这令人愉悦，而愉悦是进化激励我们做出适应性行为的方式。
Horror is pleasurable to many people because it lets us play with negative emotions and develop coping strategies.
对许多人来说，恐怖作品之所以令人愉悦，是因为它让我们能以玩的心态去体验负面情绪，并形成应对策略。
We learn what it feels like to be truly afraid, and we learn how to handle negative emotion.
我们会了解到真正害怕是一种什么感觉，也会学会如何处理负面情绪。
How, then, does horror work?
那么，恐怖作品是如何起作用的呢？
My research suggests that horror works by exploiting an ancient set of biological defence mechanisms—an evolved fear system, which we share with other animals.
我的研究表明，恐怖作品是通过利用一套古老的生物防御机制起作用的——一种进化而来、我们与其他动物共有的恐惧系统。
But humans are uniquely imaginative, and we use our evolved imagination to travel into virtual worlds that are full of danger.
但人类有着独一无二的想象力，我们会运用进化而来的想象力，进入充满危险的虚拟世界。
There are good reasons for watching a horror film, even if you’re not a loyal horror fan.
即使你并不是恐怖片的忠实粉丝，也有充分的理由去看恐怖片。
If you make it through the film in one piece, you’ll probably experience a strong sense of mastery, a sense that you were able to make it through an appalling experience.
如果你安然无恙地熬过了这部电影，很可能会体验到一种强烈的掌控感，觉得自己成功熬过了一段骇人的经历。
Anyway, watching a horror film makes you better at handling your own fear, and who knows when that will become critically relevant?
不管怎样，看恐怖片能让你更善于处理自己的恐惧，而谁知道这种能力什么时候会变得至关重要呢？